歌词大意:自从那一天
* From the day we arrive *
我们来到这个星球
* On the planet *
眨着眼走进阳光
* And, blinking, step into the sun *
想看的
* There's more to see *
永远看不够
* Than can ever be seen *
想做的
* More to do *
永远做不完
* Than can ever be done *
想要学的
* There's far too much *
永远没有尽头
* To take in here *
想寻找的
* More to find *
永远那么多
* Than can ever be found *
但日出日落
* But the sun rolling high *
穿过蓝天
* Through the sapphire sky *
把伟大和渺小
* Keeps great and small *
融入无尽的轮回
* On the endless round *
这是生命的轮回
* It's the circle of life *
让所有人
* And it moves us all *
体验绝望和希望
* Through despair and hope *
忠诚和爱情
* Through faith and love *
直到找到自己
* Till we find our place *
一条只有一个方向的
* On the path unwinding *
轮回之路
* In the circle *
生命的轮回
* The circle of life *
这是生命的轮回
* It's the circle of life *
让所有人
* And it moves us all *
体验绝望和希望
* Through despair and hope *
忠诚和爱情
* Through faith and love *
直到找到自己
* Till we find our place *
一条只有一个方向的
* On the path unwinding *
轮回之路
* In the circle *
生命的轮回
* The circle of life *
生活是不公平的  对不对
Life's not fair, is it?
比如   我...  国王永远不是我.
You see, I...  Well, I shall never be king.
还有你...  永远见不到明天的阳光.
And you shall never see  the light of another day.
再见.
Adieu.
你妈妈没有告诉过你不要拿食物玩吗
Didn't your mother tell you not to play with your food?
你来做什么
What do you want?
我来通知国王Mufasa即将驾临
I'm here to announce that King Mufasa's on his way.
你最好为自己没有参加早上的庆典
So you'd better have a good excuse...
找个好借口.
for missing the ceremony this morning.
看   Zazu. 你弄丢了我的午餐.
Oh, now, look, Zazu. You've made me lose my lunch.
如果国王来了
Ha! You'll lose more than that...
你失去的就不止是那个.
when the king gets through with you.
他像一头发狂的河马.
He's as mad as a hippo with a hernia.
我怕得发抖!
Oooh. I quiver with fear!
Scar   别那样子看我.
Now, Scar, don't look at me that way.
救救我!
Help!
放下他.
Drop him.
来得正是时候  陛下.
Impeccable timing, Your Majesty.
大哥怎么会屈尊
Why, if it isn't my big brother...
到普通百姓这儿来.
descending from on high to mingle with the commoners.
Sarabi和我在Simba的庆典上没见到你.
Sarabi and I didn't see you at the presentation of Simba.
是今天举行吗
That was today?
太可怕了!
Ohh, I feel simply awful!
肯定是我搞错了.
Must've slipped my mind.
没错   是你太滑头了
Yes, well, as slippery as your mind is...
作为国王的弟弟
as the king's brother...
你应该站在队伍的第一位!
you should've been first in line!
我一直是第一位
Well, I was first in line...
直到这个小毛球出生.
until the little hairball was born.
那小毛球是我的儿子
That hairball is my son...
也是你们未来的国王.
and your future king.
我应该练习自己的礼仪!
I shall practice my curtsy.
不要给我脸色看   Scar.
Don't turn your back on me, Scar.
不   Mufasa.
Oh, no, Mufasa.
也许是你不该给我脸色.
Perhaps you shouldn't turn your back on me.
想挑战我吗
Is that a challenge?
别发火   别发火.
Temper, temper.
我从未想过挑战你.
I wouldn't dream of challenging you.
真遗憾. 为什么不
Pity. Why not?
论聪明才智  我有狮子的天份.
As far as brains go, I got the lion's share.
但说到残忍的力量...
But when it comes to brute strength...
恐怕我没有多少
I'm afraid I'm at the shallow end...
狮子的基因.
of the gene pool.
每个家族都有这么一个的  陛下.
There's one in every family, sire.
事实上  我们家有两个 -他们总是想
Two in mine, actually, and they always manage...
破坏一些特殊场合.
to ruin special occasions.
我该怎么处置他
What am I going to do with him?
他做条地毯很不错.
He'd make a very handsome throw rug.
想一下   只要他弄脏自己
And just think, whenever he gets dirty...
你就可以把他拖出去打.
you could take him out and beat him.
辛巴.
Simba.
爸爸!
Dad! Dad!
快点儿   爸爸   我们得走了! 醒醒!
Come on, Dad, we gotta go! Wake up
对不起.
Sorry.
爸爸!
Dad. Dad.
你儿子醒了.
Your son is awake.
爸爸!爸爸!爸爸..
Dad, Dad, Dad...
太阳升起前  他是你的儿子.
Before sunrise, he's your son.
快点儿   爸爸
Dad! Come on, Dad.
爸爸
Dad!
你答应过我的.
You promised.
-好了.我起来.  -太好了
-OK, OK. I'm up.  -Yeah!
看  辛巴.
Look, Simba.
有阳光的地方都是我们的王国.
Everything the light touches is our kingdom.
哇
Wow.
国王作为统治者
A king's time as ruler...
总是像太阳一样升起落下.
rises and falls like the sun.
有一天   辛巴   我就会像太阳一样落山
One day, Simba, the sun will set on my time here...
而你就会作为新国王  像太阳一样升起.
and will rise with you as the new king.
-那样这都会成为我的  -一切.
-And this'll all be mine?  -Everything.
所有阳光能抵达的地方.
Everything the light touches.
那么黑暗的地方呢
What about that shadowy place?
那是我们的边界.
That's beyond our borders.
你绝对不能去那儿   辛巴.
You must never go there, Simba.
我觉得国王可以做任何他想做的事.
But I thought a king can do whatever he wants.
做国王不止这些
There's more to being king...
不能单凭勇气.
than getting your way all the time.
-不止这些?   -辛巴...!
-There's more?  -Simba...
你所见到的事物
Everything you see exists together...
都存在一种非常微妙的平衡关系
in a delicate balance.
作为国王   你要懂得这种平衡
As king, you need to understand that balance...
并尊重所有生物
and respect all the creatures...
不管是蚂蚁还是羚羊.
from the crawling ant to the leaping antelope.
可是  爸爸  我们不是吃羚羊吗
But, Dad, don't we eat the antelope?
没错  辛巴  我解释给你听.
Yes, Simba, but let me explain.
我们死后身体会变成草
When we die, our bodies become the grass...
而羚羊吃草.
and the antelope eat the grass.
所以在生命循环中
And so we are all connected...
我们大家是相互联系的.
in the great circle of life.
-早上好   陛下!  -早上好   Zazu.
-Good morning, sire!  -Good morning, Zazu.
汇报上午报告.
Checking in with the morning report.
开始吧.
Fire away.
歌词大意: 黑猩猩在疯狂
* Chimps are going ape *
长颈鹿仍是高高在上
* Giraffe remain above it all *
大象们想起
* Elephants remember *
是什么  我已记不起
* Though just what, I can't recall *
鳄鱼们正在争抢
* Crocodiles are snapping up *
河岸上的新鲜礼品
* Fresh offers from the banks *
对我的鸟蛋产生了兴趣
* Shown interest in my nest egg *
但我马上拒绝了
* But I quickly said no thanks *
我们还没有付犀鸟们钱
* We haven't paid the hornbills *
秃鹫有了预感
* And the vultures have a hunch *
没有邀请大家
* Not everyone invited *
但吃完午饭后会回来
* Will be coming back from lunch *
这是上午报告
* This is the morning report *
有长的也有短的
* Gives you the long and the short *
又烦又闹又不寻常
* It's every grunt, roar, and snort *
不是我编的故事
* It's not a tale I distort *
上午报告
* On the morning report *
你在做什么  儿子
What are you doing, son?
扑击.
Pouncing.
让老手教你怎么做吧.
Let an old pro show you how it's done.
野牛们在发牢骚
* Oh, the buffalo have got a beef *
离地面低点儿.
Stay low to the ground.
好的. 离地面低点儿.
OK. Stay low to the ground.
不要出声.
Not a sound.
所有牧群的季节色是藏红
* Saffron is this season's colour Seen in all the herds *
慢慢地.
Take it slow.
再走一步...
One more step...
然后...
then...
这是上午报告
* This is the morning report *
有长的也有短的
* Gives you the long and the short *
又烦又闹又不寻常
* Every grunt, roar, and snort *
不是我编的故事
* Not a tale I distort *
上午报告
* On the morning report *
很好.
That's very good.
-Zazu!  -是!
-Zazu!  -Yes!
长官!地下新闻
Sir! News from the underground.
现在   这一次...
Now, this time...
陛下! 鬣狗到荣誉大地来了!
Sire! Hyenas in the pride lands!
Zazu   带 辛巴 回家.
Zazu, take Simba home.
爸爸   我能不能去
Aw, dad, can't I come?
不行   儿子.
No, son.
我总是哪儿也不能去.
I never get to go anywhere.
殿下   你将来要做国王的.
Oh, young master, one day you will be king.
那时你就可以去驱逐这些贪婪   肮脏  愚蠢地偷猎者了
Then you can chase those slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers
从早到晚.
from dawn until dusk.
喂   Scar叔叔! 猜一猜
Hey, Uncle Scar! Guess what?
我讨厌猜迷游戏.
I despise guessing games.
我将会成为荣誉石国王.
I'm gonna be King of Pride Rock.
很好!
Oh, goody!
爸爸刚才带我看了整个王国
My dad just showed me the whole kingdom,
我要成为它的统治者!
and I'm gonna rule it all!
好. 原谅我没有高兴地跳起来.
Yes. Well, forgive me for not leaping for joy.
背不好  你知道的.
Bad back, you know.
Scar叔叔. 如果我做了国王   那你做什么
Hey, Uncle Scar. When I'm king, what'll that make you?
一只猴子的叔叔.
A monkey's uncle.
-你真怪.  -你不会了解的.
-You're so weird.  -You have no idea.
那么说  你父亲给你看了整个王国  是吗
So, your father showed you the whole kingdom, did he?
所有一切.
Everything.
他没带你去北部边界以外看一看吗
He didn't show you what's beyond that rise at the northern border?
没有. 他说我不能去那儿.
Well, no. He said I can't go there.
他是对的.
And he's absolutely right.
那儿太危险了.
It's far too dangerous.
只有最勇敢地狮子敢去那儿.
Only the bravest lions go there.
我很勇敢的. 那儿有什么
Well, I'm brave. What's out there?
对不起   辛巴 我不能告诉你.
I'm sorry, Simba, I just can't tell you.
为什么
Why not?
我要照顾我亲爱侄子的健康.
I'm only looking out for the well-being of my favourite nephew.
对! 我是你唯一的侄子.
Yeah, right! I'm your only nephew.
还有许多要保护你的原因.
All the more reason for me to be protective.
象冢不是王子去的地方. 噢!
An elephant graveyard is no place for a young prince. Oops!
象的什么
An elephant what?
亲爱的   我说得太多了.
Oh, dear, I've said too much.
我觉得你迟早会知道的
Well, I suppose you'd have found out sooner or later,
你这么聪明.
you being so clever and all.
帮我一个忙.
Just do me one favour.
答应我你永远不会去那恐怖的地方.
Promise me you'll never visit that dreadful place.
没问题.
No problem.
好孩子.
There's a good lad.
出去去玩吧.
You run along now and have fun.
这是我们之间的秘密.
it's our little secret.
-嗨   Nala.  -嗨  辛巴.
-Hey, Nala.  -Hi, Simba.
来. 我刚听说一个好地方.
Come on. I just heard about this great place.
辛巴! 我正在洗澡.
Simba! I'm kind of in the middle of a bath.
你也该洗了.
And it's time for yours.
妈妈!
Mom!
妈妈   你把我的头发弄乱了!
Mom, you're messing up my mane!
好了   我干净了. 现在我可以走了吗
OK, I'm clean. Can we go now?
那么   我们去哪儿
So, where are we going?
最好不是无聊的地方.
It better not be anyplace dumb.
不是  那地方很酷的
No, it's really cool.
那么  这个很酷的地方在哪儿
So, where is this really cool place?
-在水坑周围.  -水坑
-Around the water hole.  -The water hole?
水坑周围有什么好
What's so great about the water hole?
到那儿我就告诉你.
I'll show you when we get there.
妈妈   我能和辛巴去吗
Mom, can I go with Simba?
你觉得呢   Sarabi
What do you think, Sarabi?
这个...
Well...
求求你
Please?
我没意见.
It's all right with me.
-太好了!  -好吧!
-Yeah!  -All right!
只要 Zazu 和你一起去.
As long as Zazu goes with you.
不, 不是 Zazu.
No, not Zazu.
走快点儿.
Step lively.
我们越早赶到水坑  就可以越早离开.
The sooner we get to the water hole, the sooner we can leave.
我们要去哪儿
So, where are we really going?
象冢.
An elephant graveyard.
啊!
Wow!
对. 那我们怎么甩掉这个糊涂蛋
Right. So, how are we gonna ditch the dodo?
看你们俩个.
Oh, just look at you two.
浪漫的种子在大草原上开花.
Little seeds of romance blossoming in the savanna.
你们的父母会感到惊喜的
Your parents will be thrilled,
为你还有你的未婚妻.
what with your being betrothed and all.
什么
Be-what?
婚约.
Betrothed. Intended.
订婚.
Affianced.
什么意思...
Meaning...?
将来   你们要结婚的.
One day, you two are going to be married.
我不能娶她. 她是我的朋友.
I can't marry her. She's my friend.
对  感觉很怪
Yeah, it'd be so weird.
对不起  我不该绝你们的念头
Sorry to bust your bubble,
但你们没有选择.
but you two turtle doves have no choice.
这是世代相传的风俗.
It's a tradition going back generations.
我当国王时   第一件事就要废除它.
When I'm king, that'll be the first thing to go.
只要有我在就没门儿.
Not so long as I'm around.
那样的话  你会被开除.
In that case, you're fired.
做得不错   但只有国王可以这么做.
Nice try, but only the king can do that.
他是未来的国王.
Well, he's the future king.
没错   所以你得按我说的做.
Yeah, so you have to do what I tell you.
不行  我不会的.
Not yet, I don't.
以那种态度
And with an attitude like that,
我担心你会变成一个很可怜的国王  真的.
I'm afraid you're shaping up to be a pretty pathetic king, indeed.
我不这么看.
Not the way I see it.
歌词大意:我将成为强大的国王
* I'm gonna be a mighty king *
所以敌人们都要小心
* So enemies beware *
我从未见过一个兽王
* Well, I've never seen a king of beasts *
只有这一丁点儿头发
* With quite so little hair *
我将会万众注目
* I'm gonna be the main event *
超越历代国王
* Like no king was before *
我整装打扮  俯视众生
* I'm brushin' up on lookin' down *
练习吼声
* I'm workin' on my roar *
目前为止还很平凡
* Thus far, a rather uninspiring thing *
我迫不及待要当国王
* Oh, I just can't wait to be king *
你要走的路还很长   殿下   如果你觉得...
You've rather a long way to go, young master, if you think...
-没人说' "这么做"  -我是说...
-* No one sayin', "do this" *  -Now, when I said that...
-没人说   "到那儿"  -我的意思是...
-* No one saying, "be there" *  -What I meant was...
-没人说' "那样不行"  -你还不知道...
-* No one sayin', "stop that" *  -But what you don't realise...
-没人说' "看这儿"  -看这边!
-* No one sayin', "see here" *  -Now, see here!
每天自由自在地奔跑
* Free to run around all day *
那肯定是越界了.
Well, that's definitely out.
随心所欲地做任何事
* Free to do it all my way *
我认为现在你和我
* I think it's time that you and I *
应该交下心
* Arranged a heart-to-heart *
国王不需要
* Kings don't need advice *
小犀鸟的建议
* From little hornbills for a start *
如果这是君主制度的方向
* If this is where the monarchy is headed *
淘汰我吧
* Count me out *
赶我走  离开非洲
* Out of service, out of Africa *
我不会逗留
* I wouldn't hang about *
这孩子心比天野
* This child is getting wildly out of wing *
我迫不及待要当国王
* Oh, I just can't wait to be king *
大家   向左看
* Everybody, look left *
大家  向右看
* Everybody, look right *
不管向哪边看
* Everywhere you look, I'm *
我都是万众注目的中心
* Standing in the spotlight *
还不是!
Not yet!
所有生灵都尽情歌唱吧
* Let every creature go for broke and sing *
让我们一起自由自在地欣赏
* Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing *
这是国王辛巴最奔放地舞蹈
* It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling *
我迫不及待要当国王
* Oh, I just can't wait to be king *
我迫不及待
* Oh, I just can't wait *
要当国王
* To be king *
对不起   夫人   我...
I beg your pardon, madam, but...
走开!
Get off!
辛巴
Simba?
Nala!
好了! 这主意真不错!
All right! It worked!
我们甩掉他了.
We lost him.
我是个天才
I am a genius.
嗨   天才  这是我的主意.
Hey, genius, it was my idea.
没错   但是我实施的.
Yeah, but I pulled it off.
-还有我!  -是吗
-With me!  -Oh, yeah?
-压住你了.  -让我起来!
-Pinned ya.  -Hey, let me up!
又压住你了.
Pinned ya again.
是这儿. 我们到了.
This is it. We made it.
真可怕.
It's really creepy.
对.
Yeah.
是不是很棒
Isn't it great?
我们可能会有大麻烦的.
We could get in big trouble.
我知道!
I know!
不知道它的脑子还在不在
I wonder if its brains are still in there.
只有一个办法能知道.
There's only one way to know.
来   我们去看一看.
Come on, let's go check it out.
不对! 你要做的只有
Wrong! The only checking out you will do
-离开这儿.  -老兄!
-Will be to check out of here.  -Oh, man!
我们越过荣誉大地的边界了
We're way beyond the boundary of the pride lands.
看呀   香蕉嘴害怕了.
Look, banana beak is scared.
对你来说是香蕉嘴先生   乳臭未干的小子
It's Mr banana beak to you, fuzzy,
现在我们的处境很危险.
and right now we are all in very real danger.
危险 哈!
Danger? Ha!
我想到哪儿就到哪儿.
I walk on the wide side.
我笑对危险.
I laugh in the face of danger.
啊哈   Banzai   那是什么人
Well, well, well, Banzai, what have we got here?
我不知道   Shenzi.
I don't know, Shenzi.
你觉得呢   Ed
What do you think, Ed?
和我想的一样.
Just what I was thinking.
三个私闯禁地的人!
A trio of trespassers!
这是个意外 我向你保证.
And quite by accident, let me assure you.
导航系统有点错误.
A simple navigational error.
站住.
Whoa, wait.
我认识你. 你是 Mufasa的手下.
I know you. You're Mufasa's little stooge.
我   夫人   是国王的 首席笃么士.
l, madam, am the king's major-domo.
那你是...
And that would make you...
未来的国王.
The future king.
你知道我会怎么对付 走出自己领地的国王吗
Do you know what we do to kings who step out of their kingdom?
哼! 你不能对我怎么样.
Huh! You can't do anything to me.
从法律上讲   他们可以. 我们是在他们的领地.
Technically, they can. We are on their land.
可你告诉我他们只是些贪婪   肮脏  愚蠢的捕猎者.
But you told me they're nothing but slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers.
此一时彼一时.
lx-nay on the upid-stay.
你说什么
Who are you callin' upid-stay?
看太阳!
Oh, look at the sun!
-我们该走了!  -急什么
-It's time to go!  -What's the hurry?
我们想留你吃晚饭.
We'd love you to stick around for dinner.
对   我们可以吃所有 用狮子可以做的东西!
Yeah, we could have whatever's lion around!
等等   等等   我有了   我有了!
Wait, wait, wait, I got one, I got one!
给我做个嫩肉三明治吧! 你觉得怎么样
Make mine a cub sandwich! Whaddaya think?
怎么了   Ed 怎么了
What, Ed? What is it?
喂  我们让晚饭走了吗
Hey, did we order this dinner to go?
没有   怎么了
No, why?
因为他们跑了!
Cos there it goes!
-我们甩掉他们了  -我想是.
-Did we lose 'em?  -I think so.
Zazu呢
Where's Zazu?
首席笃么士鸟一路
The little major-domo bird hippety-hopped
跳进鸟锅里.
all the way to the birdie-boiler.
不行! 鸟锅不行!
Oh, no! Not the birdie-boiler!
喂   你们为什么不挑一个 和你们个头差不多的
Hey, why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
比如你
Like you?
在这儿   小猫咪   小猫咪   小猫咪.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
就这个样子
That was it?
再来一次. 快点儿.
Do it again. Come on.
-饶命! 大叔!  -安静!
-Oh, please! Uncle!  -Silence!
-我们刚打算闭嘴的!  -真对不起.
-We're gonna shut up right now!  -We're really sorry.
如果再靠近我儿子...
If you ever come near my son again...
它是你儿子
Oh, this is... this is your son?
-你儿子  -你以前知道吗
-Oh, your son?  -Did you know that?
不知道.我 我不知道... 不知道   你呢
No. Me? I didn't know... No, did you?
-不知道   当然不知道.  -不知道.
-No, of course not.  -No.
再见.
Toodles.
-爸爸   我...  -你没听我的话.
-Dad, I...  -You deliberately disobeyed me.
-爸爸 我... 对不起.  -我们回家吧.
-Dad, I'm... I'm sorry.  -Let's go home.
我觉得你很勇敢.
I thought you were very brave.
是   陛下
Yes, sire?
带 Nala 回家. 我要教教我儿子.
Take Nala home. I've got to teach my son a lesson.
走吧  Nala.
Come, Nala.
辛巴... 祝你好运.
Simba... good luck.
辛巴   我对你很失望.
Simba, I'm very disappointed in you.
-我知道.  -你差点儿被杀了.
-I know.  -You could've been killed.
你没有听我的话
You deliberately disobeyed me,
更糟的是   你让 Nala 也陷入险境.
and what's worse, you put Nala in danger.
我只是想勇敢些   像你一样.
I was just trying to be brave, like you.
我只在需要勇敢时才勇敢.
I'm only brave when I have to be.
勇敢
Being brave
不是指你自己去找麻烦.
doesn't mean you go looking for trouble.
但你什么也不怕.
But you're not scared of anything.
今天我是这样.
I was today.
-今天?   -对.
-You were?  -Yes.
我以为要失去你.
I thought I might lose you.
原来国王也会害怕.
I guess even kings get scared.
-但你知道吗?  -什么?
-But you know what?  -What?
我觉得这些鬣狗更害怕.
I think those hyenas were even scareder.
因为没有人敢和你爸爸乱来.
Cos nobody messes with your dad.
-来这儿   你.  -不要!
-Come here, you.  -Oh, no!
抓到你了!
Gotcha!
-我们是好朋友 对吗?  -对.
-We're pals, right?  -Right.
我们会永远在一起的  对吗
And we'll always be together, right?
辛巴  我告诉你一些
Simba, let me tell you something
我父亲曾告诉我的事情.
that my father told me.
看那些星星.
Look at the stars.
那些曾经的伟大国王
The great kings of the past
会从那些星星那儿俯视我们.
Iook down on us from those stars.
-真的?  -对.
-Really?  -Yes.
所以你感到孤独时
So whenever you feel alone,
只要记着这些国王
just remember that those kings
会一直在那儿守护着你.
will always be there to guide you.
我也一样.
And so will I.
老兄   都是那个大嗓门的Mufasa. 我一个星期都无法坐了.
Man, that lousy Mufasa. I won't be able to sit for a week.
这并不好笑   Ed.
It's not funny, Ed.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
你们能不能住手
Will you knock it off?
-是他先动手的.  -看看你们自己.
-Well, he started it.  -Look at you guys.
难怪我们只能在 食物链的底部晃来晃去.
No wonder we're dangling at the bottom of the food chain.
老兄   我讨厌晃来晃去.
Man, I hate dangling.
是吗 如果没有这些狮子   我们就会是老大.
Yeah? If it weren't for those lions, we'd be runnin' the joint.
老兄   我讨厌狮子.
Man, I hate lions.
-盛气凌人.  -粗鲁.
-So pushy.  -And hairy.
-卑鄙.  -还有  他们...
-And stinky.  -And, man, are they...
很丑陋!
Ugly!
我们狮子才没那么差
Surely we lions are not all that bad.
Scar. 是你啊.
Oh, Scar. It's just you.
我们还以为是很重要的人物呢.
We were afraid it was somebody important.
对   比如   Mufasa.
Yeah, you know, like Mufasa.
-对.  -我知道.
-Yeah.  -I see.
-那是权力!  -给我讲讲.
-Now that's power!  -Tell me about it.
我听到那名字就发抖.
I just hear that name and I shudder.
再来一次.
Do it again.
它让我激动.
It tingles me.
我周围是一群笨蛋.
I'm surrounded by idiots.
你   Scar   我是说   你是我们一员. 我是说   你是我们的好朋友.
Now, you, Scar, I mean, you're one of us. I mean, you're our pal.
不胜荣幸.
Charmed.
我喜欢.他虽然不是国王   但仍然这么正经.
Oh, I like that. He's not king, but he's still so proper.
喂   你有没有给我们带吃的
Hey, did you bring us anything to eat,
Scar   老伙计   老朋友 带了吗
Scar, old buddy, old pal? Did ya?
我觉得你们不配吃这个.
I don't think you really deserve this.
我只是将它作为礼物给你们
I practically gift-wrapped those cubs for you,
你们连他们也干不掉.
and you couldn't even dispose of them.
你知道...
Well, you know...
它们并没有落单   Scar.
it wasn't exactly like they was alone, Scar.
对. 我们该怎么做
Yeah. What were we supposed to do?
杀了 Mufasa
Kill Mufasa?
完全正确.
Precisely.
我清楚你们的记忆力
* I know that your powers of retention *
和野猪的屁股一样臭
* Are as wet as a warthog's backside *
但你们虽然笨    注意听
* But thick as you are, pay attention *
我的话是一种荣誉
* My words are a matter of pride *
你们愚蠢的脑瓜儿也会明白
* It's clear from your vacant expressions *
阳光不总是高高在上
* The lights are not all on upstairs *
但我们说的是国王和继位
* But we're talking kings and successions *
即使你们也不会轻易被逮到
* Even you can't be caught unawares *
所以为千载难逢的机会做好准备
* So prepare for the chance of a lifetime *
为轰动新闻做好准备
* Be prepared for sensational news *
一个新时代正悄悄走近
* A shiny new era is tiptoeing nearer *
我们能做点什么
And where do we feature?
听老师讲
* Just listen to teacher *
我知道听起来卑鄙
* I know it sounds sordid *
但你们会得到回报的
* But you'll be rewarded *
在我最终得到应得的权益
* When at last I am given my dues *
正义得到伸张之时
* And injustice deliciously squared *
准备好
* Be prepared *
对   准备好. 我们准备好. 做什么
Yeah, be prepared. We'll be prepared. For what?
杀死国王.
For the death of the king.
-他是不是有病  -不   笨蛋   我们要杀了他.
-Why, is he sick?  -No, fool, we're going to kill him.
-还有辛巴.  -好主意. 谁会需要国王
-And Simba, too.  -Great idea. Who needs a king?
不要国王   不要国王
* No king, no king *
-笨蛋! 应该有国王!  -但你说...
-Idiots! There will be a king!  -But you said...
我做国王!
I will be king!
跟着我
Stick with me,
你们就再也不会挨饿.
and you'll never go hungry again.
-对! 好!  -国王万岁!
-Yeah! All right!  -Long live the king!
国王万岁!
Long live the king!
太妙了  我们很快就会结盟
* It's great that we'll soon be connected *
和一个受人敬仰的国王
* With a king who'll be all-time adored *
当然  代价是   你们要
* Of course, quid pro quo, you're expected *
履行一些职责
* To take certain duties on board *
未来充满了奖赏
* The future is littered with prizes *
虽然我是主要获利者
* And though I'm the main addressee *
但我必须强调一点
* The point that I must emphasise is *
没有我你们什么也得不到!
* You won't get a sniff without me! *
所以为世纪行动作好准备
* So prepare for the coup of the century *
为最阴暗的诡计作好准备
* Be prepared for the murkiest scam *
精心计划
* Meticulous planning *
顽强中包含着
* Tenacity spanning *
数十年的忍耐
* Decades of denial *
是我成为国王的原因  毫无争议
* Is simply why I'll be king undisputed *
受人尊敬   赞扬
* Respected, saluted *
被视为奇迹
* And seen for the wonder I am *
对   我的利齿和雄心一起暴露
* Yes, my teeth and ambitions are bared *
准备好
* Be prepared *
对   我们的利齿和雄心一起暴露
* Yes, our teeth and ambitions are bared *
准备好
* Be prepared *
你在这儿等着.
Now, you wait here.
你父亲要给你一个惊喜.
Your father has a marvelous surprise for you.
是什么
Ooh, what is it?
如果告诉你   就不会是惊喜了  对吗
If I told you, it wouldn't be a surprise.
如果你告诉我   我仍然可以装作惊喜的样子.
If you tell me, I'll still act surprised.
你真是个淘气的孩子.
You are such a naughty boy.
-告诉我吧   Scar叔叔.
-Come on, Uncle Scar.
-不行   不行.
No, no, no, no, no.
这是为你和你爸爸的.
This is just for you and your daddy.
你明白   一种父子...关系.
You know, a sort of father-son... thing.
我最好去找他来.
Well, I better go get him.
-我和你一起去.  -不行.
-I'll go with you.  -No!
不行. 待在这块石头上.
No. Just stay on this rock.
你不会愿意再惹乱子
You wouldn't want to end up in another mess...
就像上次那些鬣狗.
like you did with the hyenas.
-你知道这个
-You know about that?
-辛巴   大家都知道.
-Simba, everybody knows about that.
-真的  -对.
-Really?  -Oh, yes.
真幸运  爸爸救了你  是吗
Lucky Daddy was there to save you, eh?
不要告诉别人
Oh, and just between us...
你在这儿练习一下你的小嗓门吧.
you might want to work on that little roar of yours.
好吧.
Oh, OK.
嗨   Scar叔叔 我会喜欢这个惊喜吗
Hey, Uncle Scar, will I like this surprise?
辛巴  你肯定喜欢得要死.
Simba, it's to die for.
-闭嘴.  -我忍不住了.
-Shut up.  -I can't help it.
我太饿了. 我要去抓头羚羊.
I'm so hungry. I got to have a wildebeest.
不要动.
Stay put.
我挑个又小又弱的不行吗
Can't I just pick off one of the little sick ones?
不行. 我们等Scar的信号
No. We wait for the signal from Scar.
他来了. 走吧.
There he is. Let's go.
"小嗓门"!
Little roar. Puhh.
看   陛下   羚羊群在跑.
Oh, look, sire, the herd is on the move.
-奇怪.  -Mufasa   快.
-Odd.  -Mufasa, quick!
羚羊在峡谷乱窜.
Stampede in the gorge.
-辛巴在那儿.  -辛巴?
-Simba's down there.  -Simba?
Zazu   救救我!
Zazu, help me!
你爸爸来了! 抓住!
Your father is on the way! Hold on!
快点儿!
Hurry!
那儿! 树上!
There, on that tree.
抓住   辛巴!
Hold on, Simba!
Scar   太可怕了! 我们该怎么办
Oh, Scar, this is awful! What'll we do?
我回去找人帮忙   我应该这么做.
Ha! I'll go back to help, that's what I'll do.
我回去...找人帮忙
I'll go back... Oof!
爸爸!
Dad!
弟弟! 帮我一下!
Uhh! Brother! Help me!
国王万岁.
Long live the king.
不!
No!
爸爸!
Dad!
爸爸?
Dad?
爸爸   快点儿.
Dad, come on.
起来.
You got to get up.
爸爸?
Dad?
我们回家.
We got to go home.
救命!
Help!
有人吗!
Somebody!
有人吗.
Anybody.
救命.
Help.
辛巴.
Simba.
你做什么了?
What have you done?
有野牛  他想救我.
There were wildebeests, and he tried to save me.
是意外. 我不知道会发生这事.
It was an accident. I didn't mean for it to happen.
当然. 你当然不知道.
Of course, of course you didn't.
没有人知道会发生这事的.
No one ever means for these things to happen...
可是国王死了.
but the king is dead.
如果不是为你   他不会死.
And if it weren't for you, he'd still be alive.
你母亲会怎么想
What will your mother think?
-我该怎么做
-What am I going to do?
-逃跑   辛巴.
-Run away, Simba.
跑. 逃走  永远不要回来.
Run. Run away and never return.
杀了他.
Kill him.
嗨   他跑那儿去了.
Hey, there he goes. There he goes.
去抓住他.
So, go get him.
还有路  让我进去.
There ain't no way I'm going in there.
什么   你想让我像你一样出来看热闹
You want me to come out looking like you, cactus butt?
但我们得完成任务.
But we got to finish the job.
算了   反正他去那儿和死差不多了.
Well, he's as good as dead out there anyway.
如果他回来  我们就杀了他.
And if he comes back, we'll kill him.
好! 你听到了吗
Yeah! You hear that?
如果回来   我们就杀了你!
If you ever come back, we'll kill you!
Mufasa的死是场可怕的悲剧.
Mufasa's death is a terrible tragedy...
但失去辛巴   他还刚出世不久...
but to lose Simba, who had barely begun to live...
对于我, 这是个很大的个人损失.
For me, it is a deep, personal loss.
所以  我怀着沉重的心情
So, it is with a heavy heart...
继承王位.
that I assume the throne.
但是我们应该从悲痛走出来
Yet out of the ashes of this tragedy...
迎接一个新时期的到来
we shall rise to greet the dawning of a new era...
狮子和鬣狗走在一起
in which lion and hyena come together...
一个伟大光荣的未来.
in a great and glorious future.
滚蛋!
Get out of here!
我喜欢这游戏.
I love this! Bowling for buzzards.
每次都羸他们.
Gets 'em every time.
喂   Timon   你过来看下.
Hey, Timon, you better come look.
我想他还活着.
I think it's still alive.
好吧   这是什么
All righty, what have we got here?
上帝   是头狮子! 快跑   Pumbaa   快跑!
Jeez, it's a lion!  Run, Pumbaa, move it!
喂   Timon   只是头小狮子.
Hey, Timon, it's just a little lion.
看看他. 他很可爱  又独自一个
Look at him. He's so cute and all alone.
-我们能收下他吗  -Pumbaa   你疯了吗
-Can we keep him?  -Pumbaa, are you nuts?
那是头狮子. 狮子会吃了我们的.
You're talking about a lion. Lions eat guys like us.
-可他这么小.  -他会长大的.
-But he's so little.  -He's going to get bigger.
也许他会站在我们这边的.
Maybe he'll be on our side.
这是我听到的最愚蠢的话.
That's the stupidest thing I ever heard.
也许他会...
Maybe he'll...
我懂了. 他站在我们一边会怎样
Hey, I've got it. What if he's on our side?
身边有头狮子可能不是个坏主意
You know, having a lion around might not be such a bad idea.
那我们收下他?
So we're keeping him?
当然. 我们之中谁最聪明?
Of course. Who's the brains of this outfit?
当然是我.
My point exactly.
上帝   热死我了. 我们去那边乘凉去.
Jeez, I'm fried. Let's get out of here and find some shade.
-你没事吧   孩子  -我想没事.
-You OK, kid?  -I guess so.
你差点儿死了.
You nearly died.
我救了你.
I saved you.
Pumbaa 帮忙了. 一点点儿.
Well, Pumbaa helped. A little.
谢谢你们.
Thanks for your help.
喂   你去哪儿
Hey, where you going?
不知道.
Nowhere.
他看起来有点儿蓝.
Gee, he looks blue.
-他是金色的.  -不是.我是指他很忧郁.
-I'd say brownish gold.  -No. I mean he's depressed.
什么吃你
What's eating you?
没有. 他是食物链的最顶层.
Nothing. He's at the top of the food chain.
食物链!
The food chain!
那么  你从哪儿来
So, where you from?
谁会在乎呢? 我又回不去.
Who cares?  I can't go back.
你无家可归 太好了. 我们也是.
You're an outcast. That's great. So are we.
-你做什么了   孩子  -一件糟糕透顶的事.
-What'd you do, kid?  -Something terrible.
-我不想谈这个.  -我们也不想听.
-But I don't want to talk about it.  -We don't want to hear about it.
别这样   Timon. 我们可以帮上忙吗
Come on, Timon. Anything we can do?
除非你们可以改变过去.
Not unless you can change the past.
你知道吗 孩子   在这种时候   我的朋友Timon 会说
You know, kid, in times like this, my buddy Timon here says
你应该将身后放在过去中.
you got to put your behind in your past.
不对   不对
No, no, no.
-我是说..  -成熟.
-I mean...  -Amateur.
在受伤前趴下.
Lie down before you hurt yourself.
应该是将过去放在你身后.
It's you got to put your past behind you.
听着  孩子   总会有些坏事情发生的 你没有办法改变它  对吗?
Look, kid, bad things happen, and you can't do anything about it, right?
-对.  -不对!
-Right.  -Wrong!
如果世界抛弃你
When the world turns its back on you,
你就抛弃世界.
you turn your back on the world.
没人这么教过我.
Well, that's not what I was taught.
那你可能需要上一堂新课.
Then maybe you need a new lesson.
跟我说: hakuna matata.
Repeat after me: hakuna matata.
什么
What?
它的意思是 "毋须担心"
It means "no worries".
多么美妙的词
* What a wonderful phrase *
就是转瞬即逝的疯狂
* Ain't no passing craze *
它的意思是毋须担心
* It means no worries *
为你以后的日子
* For the rest of your days *
它是我们解决问题的哲学
* It's our problem-free philosophy *
-对. 是我们的左右铭.  -什么是左右铭
-Yeah. It's our motto.  -What's a motto?
什么也不是. 左右铭对你来说是什么?
Nothing. What's a motto with you?
孩子   这两个词能解决你所有的问题.
Kid, these two words will solve all your problems.
没错. 拿 Pumbaa 来讲.
That's right. Take Pumbaa, for example.
当他还是头小野猪时
* Why... when he was a young warthog *
我还是头小野猪时
* When I was a young warthog *
-很好.  -谢谢.
-Very nice.  -Thanks.
他发现他的味道缺乏魅力
* He found his aroma lacked a certain appeal *
每次饭后他可以扫清大草原
* He could clear the savanna after every meal *
我很敏感
* I'm a sensitive soul *
虽然我看起来皮很厚
* Though I seem thick-skinned *
朋友从不站在我的下风令我受伤
* And it hurt that my friends never stood down wind *
-啊   羞愧  -他感到羞愧
-* And, oh, the shame *  -* He was ashamed *
-想改掉名字  -噢   关名字什么事
-* Thought of changing my name *  -* Oh, what's in a name? *
我抬不起头
* And I got downhearted *
-你感受如何  -我每次...
-* How did you feel? *  -* Every time that I... *
Pumbaa   不能在孩子面前讲.
Pumbaa, not in front of the kids.
对不起.
Oh, sorry.
多么美妙的词
* What a wonderful phrase *
就是转瞬即逝的疯狂
* Ain't no passing craze *
它的意思是毋须担心
* It means no worries *
你以后的日子
* For the rest of your days *
对   唱吧   孩子.
Yeah, sing it, kid.
它是我们解决问题的
* It's our problem-free *
哲学
* Philosophy *
欢迎光临寒舍.
Welcome to our humble home.
-你们住这儿  -我们想住哪儿就住哪儿.
-You live here?  -We live wherever we want.
对.家就是休息的地方.
Yep. Home is where your rump rests.
真漂亮.
It's beautiful.
我饿了.
I'm starved.
我饿死了 我可以吃下一匹斑马.
I'm so hungry I could eat a whole zebra.
我们没有斑马.
We're fresh out of zebra.
羚羊呢
Any antelope?
-河马  -没有.
-Hippo?  -Nope.
听着   孩子   如果要和我们一起住   你就得吃我们吃的东西.
Listen, kid, if you live with us, you have to eat like us.
这地方好像可以弄到些食物.
Hey, this looks like a good spot to rustle up some grub.
那是什么
Eugh, what's that?
食物. 看起来如何
A grub. What's it look like?
太腻了.
Gross.
吃起来像小鸡一样.
Tastes like chicken.
粘粘地  但很好吃.
Slimy yet satisfying.
这是很少有的美味.
These are rare delicacies.
开胃  嚼起来还很脆
Piquant, with a very pleasant crunch.
你会喜欢他们的.
You'll learn to love them.
告诉你   孩子   这是伟大的生物 -
I'm telling you, kid, this is the great life -
没有约束   没有责任.
no rules, no responsibilities.
充满了乳脂.
The little cream-filled kind.
最大好处是  无牵无挂.
And best of all, no worries.
吃吧  孩子
Well, kid?
噢. Hakuna matata.
Oh, well. Hakuna matata.
粘粘地   但很好吃.
Slimy, yet satisfying.
没错.
That's it.
它的意思是毋须担心
* It means no worries *
你以后的日子
* For the rest of your days *
它是我们解决问题的
* It's our problem-free *
哲学
* Philosophy *
哈  哈  哈!
Ta-ta!
没人知道
* Nobody knows *
我的烦恼
* The trouble I've seen *
没人知道
* Nobody knows *
我的悲伤
* My sorrow *
Zazu   放轻松点儿.
Oh, Zazu, do lighten up.
唱点有动感的.
Sing something with a little bounce in it.
这个世界很小
* It's a small world after all *
不  不! 这个除外.
No, no! Anything but that.
我有一堆可爱的椰子
* I've got a lovely bunch of coconuts *
他们排成一列
* There they are a-standing in a row *
大的   小的 有的和你的头一样大
* Big ones, small ones, some as big as your head *
和Mufasa在一起我从来不用做这个
I would never have had to do this with Mufasa.
什么 你说什么
What? What did you say?
-没什么.  -你知道法律.
-Nothing.  -You know the law.
永远不要在我面前提那个名字. 我是国王!
Never ever mention that name in my presence. I am the king!
是  陛下   你是国王.
Yes, sire, you are the king.
我... 我提到它只是为了说明一下区别
I... only mentioned it to illustrate the differences
你们皇家管理方式的区别.
in your royal managerial approaches.
-嗨   老大.  -什么时间了
-Hey, boss.  -Oh, what is it this time?
-我们要和你争论一下.  -我来说这个.
-We got a bone to pick with you.  -I'll handle this.
Scar   没有食物  也没有水.
Scar, there's no food, no water.
对. 该吃晚饭了 我们不能没有发臭的主菜.
Yeah. It's dinnertime, and we ain't got no stinking entre's.
捕猎是狮子的工作.
It's the lionesses' job to do the hunting.
-对   但他们不去.  -吃了 Zazu.
-Yeah, but they won't go hunt.  -Oh, eat Zazu.
你们不会喜欢我的.
Oh, you wouldn't want me.
我的肉又硬又臭...
I'd be so tough and gamy and...
Zazu   别犯傻了. 加点蒜就行了.
Oh, Zazu, don't be ridiculous. All you need is a little garlic.
我还以为Mufasa时代日子不好过.
I thought things were bad under Mufasa.
-你说什么  -我说 Muf-...
-What did you say?  -I said Muf...
我说...
I said... Qu?pasa?
很好. 出去.
Good. Now get out.
可我们饿.
But we're still hungry.
出去!
Out!
-好大一个嗝   辛巴.  -谢谢.
-Nice one, Simba.  -Thanks.
-老兄   我吃多了.  -我也是.
-Man, I'm stuffed.  -Me, too.
我吃得像头猪.
I ate like a pig.
Pumbaa   你本来就是.
Pumbaa, you are a pig.
没错.
Oh. Right.
-Timon  -嗯
-Timon?  -Yeah?
想没想过上面那些亮晶晶的东西是什么
Ever wonder what those sparkling dots are up there?
Pumbaa   毫无疑问  我知道.
Pumbaa, I don't wonder, I know.
是吗? 是什么?
Oh?  What are they?
是萤火虫.
They're fireflies.
是粘在那又蓝又黑东西上面的萤火虫儿.
Fireflies that got stuck up in that big blueish-black thing.
噢.
Gee.
我一直以为那是沼气球
I always thought they were balls of gas
在亿万里外燃烧.
burning billions of miles away.
Pumbaa   对你来说   一切都是沼气.
Pumbaa, with you, everything's gas.
辛巴,  你觉得呢?
Simba, what do you think?
我不知道.
Well, I don't know.
快点.说说.
Oh, come on. Give.
快点. 我们都告诉你了.
Come on. We told you ours. Please?
这...
Well...
有人曾告诉我
somebody once told me
以前的国王会在上面看着我们.
that the great kings of the past are up there watching over us.
真的?
Really?
你是说许多死去的皇室成员在看我们?
You mean a bunch of royal dead guys are watching us?
谁告诉你这个的?
Who told you something like that?
-是什么书编出来的吧 -对,  很傻,  是吧
-What mook made that up? -Yeah, pretty dumb, huh?
笑死我了.
You're killing me.
是不是我以前说过的
Was it something I said?
他还活着吗?
He's alive?
是时候了.
It is time.
在森林   大森林中
* In the jungle, the mighty jungle *
今夜狮子入睡
* The lion sleeps tonight *
我听不到  伙计. 扶着我.
I can't hear you, buddy. Back me up.
Pumbaa?
-出什么事了?  -她要吃我!
-Hey, what's going on?  -She's going to eat me!
上帝   为什么我老得救你...
Jeez, why do I always have to save your...
不用着急   老兄. 我在这儿呢.
Don't worry, buddy. I'm here for you.
一切都会好起来的.
Everything's going to be OK.
抓住她! 咬她的头!
Get her! Bite her head!
咬她喉咙! 喉咙!
Go for the jugular! The jugular!
看见了吗  我说过他会有用处的.
See, I told you he'd come in handy.
Nala?
真是你吗?
Is it really you?
-你是谁  -是我. 辛巴.
-Who are you?  -It's me. Simba.
你怎么...?
How did you...?
你从哪儿来的?
Where did you come from?
见到你太好了!
It's great to see you!
-这是怎么回事?  -你们在做什么?
-What's goin' on here?  -What are you doing here?
我做什么?  你在这儿做什么?
What am I doing here?  What are you doing here?
喂! 怎么会事!
Hey! What's goin' on here?!
Timon   这是 Nala. 她是我最好的朋友.
Timon, this is Nala. She's my best friend.
-朋友? -对. 嗨   Pumbaa 来这儿.
-Friend?  -Yeah. Hey, Pumbaa, come over here.
Nala,  这是 Pumbaa. Pumbaa   这是Nala.
Nala, this is Pumbaa. Pumbaa, Nala.
-很高兴见到你. -我也很高兴见到你.
-Pleased to meet you.  -The pleasure is all mine.
你好 停! 让我搞清楚这件事.
How do you do? Time out!  Let me get this straight.
你认识她   她认识你.
You know her, she knows you.
但她想吃他 大家对这都没有问题吗
But she wants to eat him, and everybody's OK with this?
-我有没有想错! -放松点   Timon.
-Did I miss something?!  -Relax, Timon.
你一直在这儿等大家找你.
Wait till everyone finds out you've been here all this time.
你母亲 -她会怎么想
And your mother -what will she think?
她不必知道. 大家都不必知道.
She doesn't have to know. Nobody has to know.
他们当然应该知道. 所有人都以为你已经死了.
Of course they do. Everyone thinks you're dead.
是吗?
They do?
是的. Scar 告诉了我们惊群的事.
Yeah. Scar told us about the stampede.
他说了他还告诉你们什么
He did? What else did he tell you?
那又有什么关系 你还活着. 那就是说... 你是国王.
What else matters? You're alive. And that means... you're the king.
国王?女士 , 你们那儿狮子都不同意吗
King? Lady, have you got your lions crossed.
国王?
King?
陛下  我匍匐在你脚下.
Your Majesty, I gravel at your feet.
-停下. -不是匍匐   是屈膝.
-Stop it.  -It's not gravel, it's grovel.
不用这么做! 他不是国王 你是不是?
And don't! He's not the king. Are you?
-不是.  -辛巴!
-No.  -Simba!
不   我不是国王. 我以前可能会是
No, I'm not the king.  Maybe I was gonna be,
但那是很久以前的事了
but that was a long time ago.
我不太明白. 你是国王 但你从未告诉过我们
Let me get this straight. You're the king? And you never told us?
-没什么   我还是我.  -但是有权力.
-Look, I'm still the same guy.  -But with power.
你们能让我们单独待几分钟吗
Could you guys excuse us for a few minutes?
还管她有什么话
Whatever she has to say,
都可以在我们面前说 对不对   辛巴?
she can say in front of us, right, Simba?
你们最好走开.
Maybe you'd better go.
这就开始了. 你觉得自己了解一个人...
It starts. You think you know a guy...
Timon 和 Pumbaa -
Timon and Pumbaa -
你慢慢地会喜欢他们的.
you learn to love 'em.
什么?  这是怎么回事?
What?  What is it?
你就像刚刚死里逃生一样
It's like you're back from the dead.
你不知道这对大家意味着什么.
You don't know how much this will mean to everyone.
对我有多重要.
What it means to me.
-嗨  这没什么.  -我真的很想你.
-Hey, it's OK.  -I've really missed you.
我也想你.
I've missed you, too.
告诉你   Pumbaa. 简真臭不可闻.
I tell you, Pumbaa. This stinks.
对不起.
Oh, sorry.
不是你! 是他们!
Not you! Them!
他   她   单独在一起.
Him, her, alone.
这有什么不对
What's wrong with that?
-我已预料到会发生什么事 -什么?
-* I can see what's happening *  -What?
-他们自己还不明白  -谁
-* And they don't have a clue *  -Who?
他们已堕入爱河 而且至少会这样
* They'll fall in love and here's the bottom line *
我们的三人组合成为二人
* Our trio's down to two *
黎明甜蜜地爱抚
* The sweet caress of twilight *
到处都充满魔力
* There's magic everywhere *
除了浪漫的氛围
* And with all this romantic atmosphere *
空气中还充满灾难
* Disaster's in the air *
今晚你能感觉到爱吗
* Can you feel the love tonight? *
详和静谧的夜晚
* The peace the evening brings *
此刻的世界
* The world, for once *
与所有的生灵
* In perfect harmony *
相处是如此地融洽
* With all its living things *
要告诉她的事情很多
* So many things to tell her *
但如何让她明白
* But how to make her see *
我过去一切的真相...
* The truth about my past... *
不行  她会离开我的
* Impossible, she'd turn away from me *
他在犹豫   躲藏
* He's holding back, he's hiding *
但是什么事  我无法确定
* But what, I can't decide *
为什么他不想做国王   那个我认识的国王
* Why won't he be the king I know he is? *
那个我内心深处的国王
* The king I see inside? *
今晚你能感觉到爱吗
* Can you feel the love tonight? *
详和静谧的夜晚
* The peace the evening brings *
此刻的世界
* The world, for once *
与所有的生灵
* In perfect harmony *
相处是如此地融洽
* With all its living things *
今晚你能感觉到爱吗
* Can you feel the love tonight? *
你无须看得太远
* You needn't look too far *
悄悄走出
* Stealing through *
迷茫的夜
* The night's uncertainties *
爱就在那儿
* Love is where they are *
如果他今晚堕入爱河
* And if he falls in love tonight *
可以肯定
* It can be assumed *
他和我们一起无忧无虑的日子
* His carefree days *
都将成为历史
* With us are history *
一句话   我们的友谊
* In short, our pal *
完蛋了
* Is doomed *
这地方是不是很棒?
Isn't this a great place?
非常漂亮.
It is beautiful.
但我有点不明白.
But I don't understand something.
你并没有死.
You've been alive all this time.
但你为什么不回荣誉石
Why didn't you come back to Pride Rock?
我想出来单独过自己的生活.
Well, I just needed to get out on my own, live my own life.
我做到了   这样很好.
And I did, and it's great.
我们那边真得很需要你.
We've really needed you at home.
-没人需要我. -不  我们需要. 你是国王.
-No one needs me.  -Yes, we do. You're the king.
Nala   我们都明白这点. 我不是国王. Scar 是.
Nala, we've been through this.  I'm not the king. Scar is.
辛巴   他任由鬣狗们横行荣誉大地.
Simba, he let the hyenas take over the pride lands.
-什么 -一切都完了.
-What?  -Everything's destroyed.
那儿没有 食物  也没有水.
There's no food, no water.
如果你不赶快做点儿什么   大家都要会饿死.
If you don't do something soon, everyone will starve.
-我不能回去. -为什么?
-I can't go back.  -Why?
-你不会明白的. -什么?
-You wouldn't understand.  -What?
不行   不行   没什么关系. Hakuna matata.
No, no, no. It doesn't matter. Hakuna matata.
-什么?  -Hakuna matata.
-What?  -Hakuna matata.
这是我在这儿学到的. 有时坏事情总会发生的
It's something I learned out here.Sometimes bad things happen
你对此无能为力. 那又为什么要担心呢
and there's nothing you can do about it. So why worry?
-因为这是你的责任. -那你呢你不是也离开了吗
-Because it's your responsibility.  -Well, what about you? You left.
我离开是为了寻求帮助   而且我找到了你.
I left to find help, and I found you.
你为什么不明白 你是我们唯一的希望.
Don't you understand? You're our only hope.
-对不起. -你怎么了
-Sorry.  -What's happened to you?
-你已经不是以前我认识的辛巴了. -对.我已经变了.
-You're not the Simba I remember.  -You're right. I'm not.
-现在你满意了吧 -没有. 只有失望.
-Now are you satisfied?  -No. Just disappointed.
你知道吗你说话有点像我的父亲.
You know, you're starting to sound like my father.
很好.至少我们有一个像他.
Good. At least one of us does.
你觉得你是来教我如何生活的吗
You think you can just show up and tell me how to live my life?
你根本不知道我经历了什么.
You don't even know what I've been through.
如果你说  我就会知道.
I would if you'd just tell me.
-算了! -很好!
-Forget it!  -Fine!
她错了. 我不能回去.
She's wrong. I can't go back.
这又能证明什么?  什么都不会因此改变.
What would it prove, anyway?  It won't change anything.
你无法改变过去.
You can't change the past.
你说过你会永远在我身边的!
You said you'd always be there for me!
但你没有做到.
But you're not.
是因为我.
And it's because of me.
是我的错.
It's my fault.
喂   割掉你的舌头
Come on, will you cut it out?
不行. 还会长回来的.
Can't cut it out.  It'll grow right back.
奇怪的猴子. 别跟着我好不好
Creepy little monkey.  Will you stop following me?
-你是谁 -问题是你...是谁
-Who are you?  -The question is, who... are you?
以前我知道. 现在我不太肯定.
I thought I knew.  Now I'm not so sure.
我知道你是谁. 来这儿. 这是个秘密.
Well, I know who you are.  Come here. It's a secret.
那到底是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean, anyway?
他的意思是你是一只狒狒   而我不是.
It means you are a baboon, and I'm not.
我想你有些困惑.
I think you're a little confused.
不对! 我不会有什么困惑
Wrong! I'm not the one who's confused.
-你连自己是谁都不知道. -噢   好象你知道一样.
-You don't even know who you are.  -Oh, and I suppose you know.
我当然知道. 你是 Mufasa的儿子.
Sure do. You're Mufasa's boy.
-再见. -喂   等等!
-Bye.  -Hey, wait!
你认识我父亲
You knew my father?
-正确  -我认识你的父亲.
-Correction  -I know your father.
我本来不愿意告诉你这个
I hate to tell you this,
但他已经死了很长时间了.
but he died... a long time ago.
不对. 又错了!
Nope. Wrong again!
他还活着   我带你去见他.
He's alive, and I'll show him to you.
跟着老 Rafiki. 他认识路. 来!
You follow old Rafiki. He knows the way. Come on!
别磨蹭. 快点儿!
Don't dawdle. Hurry up!
-等等. -快点儿.
-Wait.  -Come on.
你能不能慢点儿
Would you slow down?
停!
Stop!
看下面.
Look down there.
那不是我父亲. 只是我的影子.
That's not my father.  That's just my reflection.
不对.
No.
仔细看.
Look harder.
明白了吗
You see?
他活在你体内.
He lives in you.
父亲?
Father?
辛巴   你已不记得我了.
Simba, you have forgotten me.
不. 我怎么会忘记
No. How could I?
你忘了自己是谁   所以也忘记了我.
You have forgotten who you are, and so have forgotten me.
看看你的内心深处   辛巴.
Look inside yourself, Simba.
你不应该是现在这个样子.
You are more than what you have become.
你必须在生命轮回中找到自己.
You must take your place in the circle of life.
我怎么才能找回自己? 我已经不是以前的我了.
How can I go back? I'm not who I used to be.
记住你是谁.
Remember who you are.
你是我的儿子  未来真正的国王.
You are my son and the one true king.
记住你是谁.
Remember who you are.
不! 不要离开我!
No! Please, don't leave me!
记住.
Remember.
爸爸!
Father!
不要离开我.
Don't leave me.
那是什么
What was that?
天气.
The weather.
-很特别 对不对  -对.
-Very peculiar, don't you think?  -Yeah.
看来风向变了.
Looks like the winds are changing.
变化是件好事.
Change is good.
对   但并不容易.
Yeah, but it's not easy.
我知道我必须要做的事情 但回去意味着我要直面过去
I know what I have to do but going back means I'll have to face my past.
我已经逃避太久了.
I've been running from it for so long.
为什么打我
What was that for?
没什么关系  都过去了.
It doesn't matter. It's in the past.
对   但仍然让我心痛.
Yeah, but it still hurts.
对   过去仍然会让人心痛.
Oh, yes, the past can hurt.
在我看来你仍然可以选择逃避
But the way I see it you can either run from it
或者从中学些东西
or... learn from it.
明白了吗? 你准备怎么做?
You see?  So what are you going to do?
首先   拿走你的拐杖.
First, I'm gonna take your stick.
不! 别拿拐杖!
No! Not the stick!
-你要去哪儿?  -我要回去!
-Where are you going?  -I'm going back!
很好! 走吧!离开这儿!
Good! Go on! Get out of here!
食物!
Grubs!
喂  醒醒.
Hey, wake up.
没事!没事! 是我!
It's OK! It's OK! It's me!
不准再这么做
Don't ever do that again.
食肉动物!
Carnivores!
-你们见到辛巴了吗?  -我以为他和你在一起.
-Have you guys seen Simba?  -I thought he was with you.
刚才在一起   但现在找不到他了. 他去哪儿了?
He was, but now I can't find him. Where is he?
你们在这儿找不到他!
You won't find him here!
国王回去了.
The king has returned.
真不敢相信. 他回去了!
I can't believe it. He's gone back!
回去?  你是什么意思
Gone back?  What do you mean?
喂   出什么事了?
Hey, what's goin' on here?
-这猴子是谁  -辛巴去挑战 Scar了.
-Who's the monkey?  -Simba's gone to challenge Scar.
-谁? -Scar.
-Who?  -Scar.
-谁有刀疤  -不是  它是他叔叔.
-Who's got a scar?  -No, it's his uncle.
-这猴子是他叔叔  -不是! 辛巴回去
-The monkey's his uncle?  -No! Simba's gone back
找他叔叔决斗, 要夺回王位.
to challenge his uncle, to take his place as king.
辛巴,  等等!
Simba, wait up!
-太可怕了,  对吗?   -真不相信.
-It's awful, isn't it?  -I didn't want to believe you.
是什么让你回来的
What made you come back?
我突然想到了一些东西
I finally got some sense knocked into me,
而且已经想通了.
and I've got the bump to prove it.
还有  这是我的王国.
Besides, this is my kingdom.
如果我不为它战斗  又有谁会
If I don't fight for it, who will?
-我会.  -这会很危险.
-I will.   -It's gonna be dangerous.
危险? 我笑对危险.
Danger? I laugh in the face of danger.
这一点也不好笑
I see nothing funny about this.
Timon   Pumbaa 你们来干什么
Timon, Pumbaa, what are you doing here?
为您效劳  陛下.
At your service, my liege.
我们要与你叔叔作对...
We're gonna fight your uncle... for this?
对   Timon. 这是我的家.
Yes, Timon. This is my home.
说的是你们上流社会.
Talk about your fixer-upper.
辛巴  如果这对你很重要 我们会一直支持你的.
Well, Simba, if it's important to you, we're with you to the end.
-鬣狗. 我讨厌鬣狗.  -你有没有办法
-Hyenas. I hate hyenas.  -So what's your plan
甩开这些家伙
for getting past those guys?
-活诱饵.  -好主意.
-Live bait.  -Good idea.
快点   Timon. 你们必须进行牵制
Come on, Timon. You guys have to create a diversion.
你想让我怎么做 穿上草裙跳呼拉舞
Do you want me to dress in drag and do the hula?
如果你们想吃多汁的肉
* If you're hungry for juicy meat *
吃Pumbaa吧  因为他是免费的
* Eat Pumbaa because he is a treat *
快来吃这头美味的猪
* Come on down and dine on this tasty swine *
你们只要排好队就可以了
* All you have to do is get in line *
你们是不是特别想吃
* Are you achin' *
薰猪肉
* For some bacon? *
他是一头大猪
* He's a big pig *
你们也可能成为一头大猪!
* You could be a big pig, too! *
Nala  你去找我母亲  召集狮族.
Nala, you find my mother and rally the lionesses.
我去找 Scar.
I'll look for Scar.
Sarabi!
是,  Scar?
Yes, Scar?
你的猎队哪儿去了?  他们都没有干活.
Where is your hunting party?  They're not doing their job.
Scar   没有食物. 兽群已经迁移了.
Scar, there is no food. The herds have moved on.
不对   是你们不够用心寻找.
No, you're just not looking hard enough.
已经完了. 什么也没有了.
It's over. There is nothing left.
我们只有一个选择. 离开荣誉石.
We have only one choice. We must leave Pride Rock.
-我们哪儿也不去.  -你是让我们死.
-We're not going anywhere.  -You have sentenced us to death.
-那就死吧.  -你不能这么做.
-Then so be it.  -You can't do that.
我是国王.  我可以做任何事情.
I am the king.  I can do whatever I want.
如果你有Mufasa 国王的一半...
If you were half the king Mufasa was...
我比 Mufasa 国王好十倍!
I'm ten times the king Mufasa was!
你已经死了
Mufasa? No, you're dead.
Mufasa?
Mufasa
不. 是我.
No. It's me.
辛巴! 你还活着?  怎么可能
Simba! You're alive?  How can that be?
没关系. 我回家了.
It doesn't matter. I'm home.
见到你有点意外..
I'm a little surprised to see you...
活着.
alive.
告诉一个我不撕碎你的理由.
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't rip you apart.
辛巴必须明白.
Oh, Simba, you must understand.
统治一个王国的压力...
The pressures of ruling a kingdom...
已经不属于你了  下来   Scar.
Are no longer yours. Step down, Scar.
好的   我会的   我自然会.
Oh, well, I would, naturally.
不过   有个小问题.
However, there is one little problem.
看到他们了吗
You see them?
他们认为我是国王.
They think I'm king.
我们不这么认为. 辛巴是合法的国王.
Well, we don't. Simba's the rightful king.
你选择吧   Scar.
The choice is yours, Scar.
退位  或者决斗.
Either step down or fight.
这必须要用暴力解决吗?
Oh, must this all end in violence?
我不愿意因为我死去一个家人.
I'd hate to be responsible for the death of a family member.
-对不对  Simba?  -没有用的   Scar.
-Wouldn't you agree, Simba?  -That's not gonna work, Scar.
我已经不在意这个了.
I've put it behind me.
那你忠实的臣民们呢
But what about your faithful subjects?
他们也不在意吗
Have they put it behind them?
辛巴,  他在说什么?
Simba, what is he talking about?
那么说你没有告诉他们你的小秘密.
So you haven't told them your little secret.
辛巴,  现在是你告诉他们的时候了.
Well, Simba, now's your chance to tell them.
告诉他们谁应为 Mufasa的死负责.
Tell them who is responsible for Mufasa's death.
我.
I am.
不是真的.
It's not true.
告诉我这不是真的.
Tell me it's not true.
-是真的. -明白了吗? 他承认了!
-It's true.  -You see? He admits it!
-谋杀!  -不对! 是意外.
-Murderer!  -No! It was an accident.
如果不是为你   Mufasa 不会死. 他的死是你的错!
If it weren't for you, Mufasa would be alive. It's your fault he's dead!
-你否认这个吗?  -不.
-Do you deny it?  -No.
-那你就有罪.  -不, 我不是杀人犯!
-Then you're guilty.  -No, I'm not a murderer!
辛巴你又有麻烦了
Oh, Simba, you're in trouble again,
但这次爸爸不会来救你了
but this time daddy isn't here to save you,
大家都知道为什么!
and now everyone knows why!
这有些熟悉.
Now, this looks familiar.
我是不是在哪儿见过? 我想一下.
Where have I seen this before?  Let me think.
对了. 我想起来了.
Oh, yes. I remember.
这是你父亲死前的样子.
This is just the way your father looked before he died.
这是我的小秘密.
And here's my little secret.
我杀了Mufasa.
I killed Mufasa.
杀人犯!
Murderer!
-不, 辛巴 , 求你.  -告诉他们真相.
-No, Simba, please.  -Tell them the truth.
真相?  大家的眼睛是雪亮的...
Truth?  But truth is in the eye of the behold...
好吧.
All right.
All right!
是我干的.
I did it.
让他们听见.
So they can hear you.
我杀了Mufasa!
I killed Mufasa!
对不起. 借光. 让我过去.
Excuse me. Pardon me. Comin' through. Hot stuff.
-让我出去!  -让我进来!
-Let me out!  -Let me in!
求你   不要吃我.
Please, don't eat me.
放了他们!
Drop 'em!
-喂   谁是猪?  -你是在和我说话?
-Hey, who's the pig?   -Are you talkin' to me?
-他叫他是猪!  -你是在和我说话
-He called him a pig!   -Are you talking to me?
-真不该那么做.  -你是在和我说话?!
-Shouldn't have done that.  -Are you talking to me?!
-他们叫我...  猪先生!
-Now they're in for it.  -They call me... Mr Pig!
受死吧   笨蛋...
Take that, you stupid...
接招吧!
Take that and that!
跑吧   黄肚皮!
Run, you yellow-belly!
-杀人犯.  -辛巴 求求你.
-Murderer.  -Simba, please.
-求你,  宽恕我吧. 求求你.  -你不配再活着.
-Please, have mercy. I beg you.   -You don't deserve to live.
可是   辛巴   我们是一家.
But, Simba, I am... family.
鬣狗才是真正的敌人.
It's the hyenas who are the real enemy.
是他们的错. 都是他们的主意.
It was their fault. It was their idea.
我为什么要相信你
Why should I believe you?
你以前一直在骗我.
Everything you ever told me was a lie.
你要做什么?
What are you going to do?
你不会杀了自己的叔叔的.
You wouldn't kill your own uncle.
不会的   Scar.
No, Scar.
我和你不一样.
I'm not like you.
辛巴,  谢谢你. 你真是个高尚的人.
Oh, Simba, thank you.  You are truly noble.
我会弥补我的错误的   我发誓. 我怎么才能让你相信我
I'll make it up to you, I promise. And how can I prove myself to you?
告诉我. 什么都可以.
Tell me. I mean, anything.
逃跑.
Run.
逃跑   Scar
Run away, Scar,
再也不要回来.
and never return.
好.
Yes.
当然.
Of course.
我服从...
As you wish...
陛下!
Your Majesty!
朋友.
My friends.
朋友? 他好象说过我们是敌人.
Friends? I thought he said we were the enemy.
对. 我也听到了.
Yeah. That's what I heard.
不. 我解释一下.  不  你们不明白!
No. Let me explain.  No, you don't understand!
不   我不是说... 不!
No, I didn't mean... No!
是时候了.
It is time.
还记得吗
Remember.
直至我们找到自己
* Till we find our place *
一条只有一个方向
* On the path unwinding *
的轮回之路
* In the circle *
生命的轮回
* The circle of life *
生命
* Circle of *
轮回
* Life *